<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>what we do &#8211; Babyroot Photography</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:46:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Good Governance Program</title>
		<link>./../../../good-governance-program/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../good-governance-program/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13320</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[SFR views Good Governance as a key crosscutting issue throughout all of the thematic areas in our programs. However, in addition, a direct approach to promoting good governance and civic participation is also necessary. SFR’s specific aims in Good Governance are:
• To promote good governance and full civic participation as key crosscutting issues.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-955-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-955-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>SFR views Good Governance as a key crosscutting issue throughout all of the thematic areas in our programs. However, in addition, a direct approach to promoting good governance and civic participation is also necessary. SFR’s specific aims in Good Governance are:<br />
• To promote good governance and full civic participation as key crosscutting issues.<br />
• To ensure all Rwandan people have universal access to and full participation in civic, social and economic life.<br />
• To train and advocate at all levels of government and civil society in the rights of vulnerable groups.<br />
SFR is currently implementing three projects that enhance good governance and civic participation. Firstly, with the EU and Handicap International, as of 2013, SFR has been implementing a project on “Strengthening the Civic, Social and Economic Participation of Vulnerable Populations”. The project is aimed at improving access to basic services as well as the promoting inclusive citizen participation in civic life and decision-making. Specifically, this is based on community outreach, support groups, training, literacy, education and so on.</p>
<p>Secondly, our Child Headed Households (CHH) involves an element of good governance and civic participation promotion. Within the project, SFR is responsible for advocating for improved services for CHH and other vulnerable groups, economic empowerment, training on legal issues and service delivery and facilitating children and youths in CHH to be fully incorporated members of society.</p>
<p>Similarly our Women’s Economic Empowerment involves advocacy for improved service delivery for vulnerable women, training women in good governance and promoting women’s participation in decision making.</p>
<p>In the past, SFR has also implemented a Child Rights and Protection project, which has involved training local government leaders and civil society leaders on child rights and protection. This also involved strengthening locally based ‘Child Protection Committees’ with capacity building training.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../good-governance-program/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Women &#038; Youth Economic Empowerment Program</title>
		<link>./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13312</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Strive Foundation Rwanda’s flagship Women’s Economic Empowerment Program is a big focus of the organization’s programmatic activities that focus mainly on capacity building-allowing vulnerable women to help themselves out of poverty and extreme susceptibility. For Strive Foundation Rwanda, women empowerment is about making it possible for vulnerable women in the communities to participate fully in the society through creation of off-farm jobs to fight poverty.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of Rwanda’s principal goals of Vision 2020 is to decrease the population dependent on agricultural activities to about 50% by the year 2020. Taking into account the current population growth, this would mean creating 2.2 million jobs in the off-farm sector by 2020 as a means of reducing poverty and vulnerability of Rwanda’s population.</p>
<p>There is need to create more employment opportunities especially for those who are currently unemployed; those who are underemployed; and those who are classified as the working poor-the vulnerable groups.</p>
<p>Strive Foundation Rwanda’s flagship Women’s Economic Empowerment Program is a big focus of the organization’s programmatic activities that focus mainly on capacity building-allowing vulnerable women to help themselves out of poverty and extreme susceptibility. For Strive Foundation Rwanda, women empowerment is about making it possible for vulnerable women in the communities to participate fully in the society through creation of off-farm jobs to fight poverty.</p>

<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment1" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment1/index.html'><img width="300" height="225" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-200x150.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-400x300.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-600x450.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-768x576.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1-800x600.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment1.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>
<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment2" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment2/index.html'><img width="300" height="225" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-200x150.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-400x300.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-600x450.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-768x576.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2-800x600.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment2.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>
<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment3" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment3/index.html'><img width="300" height="225" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-200x150.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-400x300.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-600x450.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-768x576.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3-800x600.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment3.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>
<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment4" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment4/index.html'><img width="300" height="298" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-300x298.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-66x66.jpg 66w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-150x150.jpg 150w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-200x199.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-300x298.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-400x397.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-600x596.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-768x762.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4-800x794.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment4.jpg 946w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>
<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment5" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment5/index.html'><img width="300" height="225" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-300x225.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-200x150.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-300x225.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-400x300.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-600x450.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-768x576.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5-800x600.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment5.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>
<a data-rel="iLightbox[postimages]" data-title="women-empowerment6" data-caption="" href='./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/women-empowerment6/index.html'><img width="300" height="169" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-300x169.jpg" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-200x113.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-300x169.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-400x225.jpg 400w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-600x338.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-768x432.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6-800x450.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2019/06/women-empowerment6.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>

<p>Empowerment is important for every vulnerable woman regardless of age. They deserve to live a life that they choose and according to the terms that are right for them. Strive Foundation Rwanda believes that <i><b>“When women are able to meaningfully participate in society their needs and rights will be heard and enforced. This means women’s safety and welfare will improve and their ability to be in control of their own lives will increase. This will have a flow on effect to children as their well-being is always naturally connected to the well-being of women.”</b></i></p>
<p><b>Program vision and mission statement</b></p>
<p>Our vision for women’s economic empowerment in Rwanda is to advance the lives of vulnerable women through improving access to equal economic opportunity. Our mission is to focus our efforts on promoting the social and economical development of Rwandan vulnerable women and girl’s to improve their rights protection, reduce gender based violence and advancing women’s economic status.</p>
<p><b>Program aims and objectives</b></p>
<p>Our aims for the women’s economic empowerment program are:</p>
<ul>
<li>To facilitate effective cooperative formation amongst vulnerable women through enhancing the skills and knowledge for cooperative management, sustainability, marketing and access to technology and services in order to enhance their economic opportunity</li>
<li>To enhance the capacity of vulnerable women for entrepreneurship and the capitalization and management of income generating activities</li>
<li>To improve access to business and financial services as well as SACCO for vulnerable women</li>
<li>To improve the capabilities of vulnerable women to engage in formal cross border trade effectively within the East African Community market through training in business management, vocational skills and entrepreneurship.</li>
</ul>
<p><b>Partners in virtue</b></p>
<p>Since 2010, SFR has partnered with Human Help Network (Germany) to provide income generating activities, cooperative management training, skills and educational support to some of the most vulnerable women.</p>
<p>Currently Strive Foundation Rwanda supports vulnerable women in cooperatives that range in their productive capacities from bricklaying to fish farming, beekeeping, weaving and rice growing.</p>
<p>We also support and encourage cooperatives to initiate rotating credit; saving and credit fund, and in some cases, create emergency support funds. This ultimately contributes to the creation of collective economic security for vulnerable women and their families.</p>
<p><b>Current projects</b></p>
<p><b>Supported projects for Amahoro Cooperative in Huye district</b></p>
<p>Strive Foundation Rwanda supports Amahoro cooperative that rears fish and grows vegetables for their economic activity in Mukura sector, Huye district. The cooperative which also keeps cattle, among its activities, was established in 2009 and today has 36 members who have come together with a common goal of fighting poverty and improving their livelihood.</p>
<p>The fish project was initiated on the 25<sup>th</sup> October 2017. Strive Foundation Rwanda, in partnership with Human Help Network, supported the cooperative by constructing for them water reservoirs, bought 4000 fish fingerlings, and buys fish food.</p>
<p>When we took up the initiative to support Amahoro cooperative, we immediately started funding them in different activities like building a big canalization which reserves water for fish ponds, brought a social worker to supervise and follow up every activity supported by Strive Foundation Rwanda. We built the canal of 72 meters to serve 4 fish ponds.</p>
<p>Besides, Strive Foundation Rwanda has continuously provided capacity building to the cooperative members through trainings in fish farming techniques, cooperative management, literacy (reading and writing), financial management and marketing.</p>
<p>Here the cooperative members contribute by draining, rehabilitating the 4 fish ponds and paying the security guard. The land also belongs to the cooperative.</p>
<p>The project is still at its implementation stage as the fish are still growing until when impact and results will be realized in August 2018 when the cooperative expects to have its first harvest of about 60,000 grown fish.</p>
<p>Strive Foundation Rwanda still supported Amahoro cooperative diary activities by building kraals (cow sheds), provided a variety of agricultural materials and built a latrine at the cooperative head premises.</p>
<p><b>Supported projects for Ingoro Ihuje Ababyeyi Cooperative in Huye district</b></p>
<p>Ingoro Ihuza Ababyeyi cooperative in Tumba, sector in Huye district is comprised vulnerable single mothers. The cooperative has a variety of economic activities including brick laying, and farming where they grow rice and vegetables. The cooperative started in 2009 and today it comprises of 32 members.</p>
<p>SFR in partnership with Human Help Network supported the cooperative with startup capital which they have used very well and currently the cooperative proudly operates with a working capital worth Rfw 11 million.</p>
<p>Strive Foundation Rwanda has so far supported the cooperative with Financial assistance worth 80,000 Euros (RFW 80 million). The money has been used to purchase land, construct office and conference room (administration block), shade where bricks are made from, brick kiln for burning bricks, plus a road and a bridge leading to the cooperative premises. Other finances were used to buy equipments including a generator, office equipment and several brick laying materials.</p>
<p>Besides Financial support, Strive Foundation Rwanda provided capacity building through training to the cooperative members in bricklaying techniques, cooperative management, literacy (reading and writing), financial management and marketing.</p>
<p>The cooperative has grown into a big organization with a sound business that is growing progressively. The cooperative working has increased from RFW 7 million to RFW 11 million today. Strive Foundation Rwanda has helped the cooperative members to help themselves out of poverty and vulnerability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../women-youth-economic-empowerment-program/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Child Rights and Women’s right Program</title>
		<link>./../../../child-rights-and-womens-right-program/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../child-rights-and-womens-right-program/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13310</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Since 2003, SFR has intervened with five key projects based around protection and promoting the rights of children. Several have already been mentioned in detail above; Early Childhood Development, Orphans and Vulnerable Children, Vocational Training for Out-of-School Youths, and People with Disabilities. In addition to this, in 2009/10, SFR partnered with the Global Fund, and the Ministry of Gender and Family Promotion (MIGEPROF)...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-953-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-953-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>Child Rights and Protection cuts across many thematic areas in SFR’s programs. However, in addition, a direct approach to protecting children is vital for the development of Rwanda. SFR’s specific aims in Child Rights and Protection are:</p>
<p>To promote the human rights of all children, including the rights of children with disabilities<br />
To promote child protection at the community, district and national level through provision of training at all levels, the judiciary and the police force<br />
To promote a reduction and eventual dissolution of child labor through advocacy, educational assistance and retention and provision of training at the community level<br />
To reduce the vulnerability of children through assistance with education, economic support, vocational training, nutritional awareness, sanitation, income generating activities and shelter, particularly for OVCs and those living in CHHs</p>
<p>Since 2003, SFR has intervened with five key projects based around protection and promoting the rights of children. Several have already been mentioned in detail above; Early Childhood Development, Orphans and Vulnerable Children, Vocational Training for Out-of-School Youths, and People with Disabilities. In addition to this, in 2009/10, SFR partnered with the Global Fund, and the Ministry of Gender and Family Promotion (MIGEPROF) to implement a child protection project in four districts: Burera, Musanze, Nyamasheke and Rusizi. The project’s main focus was to provide training at all levels on promoting and protecting child rights. This included the district police units, CBOs, local leaders from village to sector level, the Joint Action Forum, the Bar Association and child protection committees. Part of the project also focused on strengthening the capacity of Child Protection Committees to improve effectiveness.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../child-rights-and-womens-right-program/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vulnerable Families</title>
		<link>./../../../vulnerable-families/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../vulnerable-families/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13308</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[SFR is partnered with Human Help Network (Germany) to provide families with shelter and income generating activities. The family shown in the photograph below was stigmatized as a result of one of the children suffering from epilepsy. Consequently the family found it extremely difficult to find housing. SFR with HHN assisted the family by building them the house shown in the photograph below.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-967-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-967-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>SFR’s Vulnerable Families program provides housing and income generating support to those families that need it most. This can include Child Headed Households, and families facing daily stigmatization.</p>
<p>The aims of this program are:</p>
<p>• To provide IGA and cooperative management training and facilitation to enable vulnerable families to utilize ECD services<br />
• To provide shelter to the most vulnerable families</p>
<p>SFR is partnered with Human Help Network (Germany) to provide families with shelter and income generating activities. The family shown in the photograph below was stigmatized as a result of one of the children suffering from epilepsy. Consequently the family found it extremely difficult to find housing. SFR with HHN assisted the family by building them the house shown in the photograph below. In addition to living quarters for the family, the house had additional rooms to provide rental income. In addition, SFR with HHN has provided tens of Child Headed Households with proper shelter since 2011.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../vulnerable-families/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>People with Disabilities</title>
		<link>./../../../people-with-disabilities/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../people-with-disabilities/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13306</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Those groups living with disabilities, both physical and mental, are some of the most vulnerable in Rwanda, often subject to stigmatization and limited opportunity. This program aims to combat both aspects of this through the following aims:]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-965-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-965-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>Those groups living with disabilities, both physical and mental, are some of the most vulnerable in Rwanda, often subject to stigmatization and limited opportunity. This program aims to combat both aspects of this through the following aims:</p>
<p>• Advocate equal rights and opportunities for disabled groups<br />
• To promote the participation of disabled groups in civic life<br />
• To provide cooperative management training and facilitation amongst disabled groups<br />
• To provide IGA training to economically empower disabled groups<br />
• To promote the social inclusion of disabled groups</p>
<p>Starting in 2013, SFR has recently partnered with the European Union and Handicap International to provide advocacy and assistance in the promotion and participation of people with disabilities in Rwandan civic and social life.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../people-with-disabilities/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fighting Gender Based Violence</title>
		<link>./../../../fighting-gender-based-violence/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../fighting-gender-based-violence/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13304</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In the past, SFR has partnered with UN Women to implement a community-policing project in order to fight gender-based and domestic violence at the grassroots level.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-963-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-963-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>Our aims for combatting GBV are:</p>
<p>• To fight GBV with community awareness campaigns<br />
• To economically empower vulnerable women through cooperative formation, IGA facilitation, and help in accessing financial institutions</p>
<p>In the past, SFR has partnered with UN Women to implement a community-policing project in order to fight gender-based and domestic violence at the grassroots level.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../fighting-gender-based-violence/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nutrition</title>
		<link>./../../../nutrition/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../nutrition/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13302</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s nutrition program is to provide vulnerable children and youths with adequate sources of nutrition and hygiene. This program manifests in two projects; Early Childhood Development and Orphans and Vulnerable Children living in child headed households (CHH).]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-973-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-973-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s nutrition program is to provide vulnerable children and youths with adequate sources of nutrition and hygiene. This program manifests in two projects; Early Childhood Development and Orphans and Vulnerable Children living in child headed households (CHH).</p>
<p>SFR’s key aims in this program are:</p>
<p>• To provide training to parents and CHH on the importance of nutrition and hygiene within the household<br />
• To promote and introduce kitchen gardens amongst CHH<br />
• To encourage links between ECD centers and community health centers for systematic growth monitoring of young children<br />
• To provide one cow per ECD</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../nutrition/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>HIV/AIDS</title>
		<link>./../../../hiv-aids/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../hiv-aids/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13300</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s HIV/AIDS program is to improve the economic situations and livelihoods of vulnerable people infected and affected by HIV/AIDS through income generating activities support, skills and business management training. In addition, the program facilitates improved access to ARV drugs, treatment and care, and is dedicated to sensitizing communities to ensure that everyone is involved in preventing and fighting against the spread of HIV/AIDS.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-971-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-971-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s HIV/AIDS program is to improve the economic situations and livelihoods of vulnerable people infected and affected by HIV/AIDS through income generating activities support, skills and business management training. In addition, the program facilitates improved access to ARV drugs, treatment and care, and is dedicated to sensitizing communities to ensure that everyone is involved in preventing and fighting against the spread of HIV/AIDS.</p>
<p>Specifically, SFR aims to:</p>
<p>• Increased access and provision of VCT<br />
• Community sensitization on the prevention, care and treatment of HIV/AIDS<br />
• Promotion of rights for people living with HIV/AIDS<br />
• Increased assistance in IGA and cooperative formation to those groups made vulnerable by HIV/AIDS</p>
<p>This program, is conjunction with the Global Fund and the Ministry of Health, has involved participatory life-skills based HIV/AIDS education, HIV prevention events, training to empower cooperatives and their members with practical skills (e.g. income generating activities), provision of start-up capital support, for example, milk cows, and campaigns for male circumcision in Nyamasheke district.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../hiv-aids/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Community Health Workers and Tuberculosis</title>
		<link>./../../../community-health-workers-and-tuberculosis/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../community-health-workers-and-tuberculosis/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13298</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s CHWs program is to improve the health seeking behavior of TB patients and suspects as well as enhance TB health care service provision at the community level. This involves mobilizing and motivating CHWs using performance based financing; enhancing the performance of community-based health care using incentives in the form of cooperative formation and income generating activities.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-969-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-969-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>The objective of Strive Foundation Rwanda’s CHWs program is to improve the health seeking behavior of TB patients and suspects as well as enhance TB health care service provision at the community level. This involves mobilizing and motivating CHWs using performance based financing; enhancing the performance of community-based health care using incentives in the form of cooperative formation and income generating activities.</p>
<p>Our specific programmatic aims are:</p>
<p>• To improve linkages between health services and communities through mobilization of CHWs<br />
• To increase the capacity of CHWs with technical support and training on cooperative management<br />
• To improve the health seeking behavior of TB patients and suspects, increase TB detection, ensure DOTS implementation and improve follow up care</p>
<p>In 2012, the program reached 10,808 CHWs organized into 113 cooperatives. The project, funded by the Global Fund through the Ministry of Health, saw SFR implement this approach in seven districts throughout Rwanda – ultimately increasing TB detection, treatment and follow-up rates.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../community-health-workers-and-tuberculosis/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Orphans and Vulnerable Children (OVCs)</title>
		<link>./../../../orphans-and-vulnerable-children-ovcs/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../orphans-and-vulnerable-children-ovcs/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 12:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[what we do]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13296</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Strive Foundation Rwanda’s OVCs program provides ongoing support for the welfare of OVCs in Rwanda. This involves provision of school materials, school uniforms, school fees, medical insurance, nutritional training, psychosocial care and assistance in crops production. In addition, support to the most vulnerable families, many of which are headed by children, is provided in the school holidays through various entertainment activities. For example, sports, poetry, singing, dance and continued psychosocial care through group meetings.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="pgc-961-0-0" class="panel-grid-cell">
<div id="panel-961-0-0-0" class="so-panel widget widget_sow-editor panel-first-child panel-last-child" data-index="0">
<div class="so-widget-sow-editor so-widget-sow-editor-base">
<div class="siteorigin-widget-tinymce textwidget">
<p>Strive Foundation Rwanda’s OVCs program provides ongoing support for the welfare of OVCs in Rwanda. This involves provision of school materials, school uniforms, school fees, medical insurance, nutritional training, psychosocial care and assistance in crops production. In addition, support to the most vulnerable families, many of which are headed by children, is provided in the school holidays through various entertainment activities. For example, sports, poetry, singing, dance and continued psychosocial care through group meetings.</p>
<p>Our specific aims are:</p>
<p>• To identify minimum package priority for OVCs in education.<br />
• To provide social and economic protection to CHH and OVCs.<br />
Funded by HHN since 2011, SFR has successfully provided support to many CHH and OVCs, whom have been orphaned due to genocide, HIV/AIDS, malaria or war. This support helped these children and young people to gain access to proper education, health, nutrition, shelter, psychosocial care and ultimately improved economic situations throughout 3 districts of Rwanda. In addition, SFR has supported the training and initiation of youth cooperatives, in order to provide long-term economic support and income generating activities for OVCs.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../orphans-and-vulnerable-children-ovcs/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
