<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Babyroot Photography</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 12:02:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How community outreach programmes fight stigma for disabled school-going children in Musanze</title>
		<link>./../../../how-community-outreach-programmes-fight-stigma-for-disabled-school-going-children-in-musanze/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../how-community-outreach-programmes-fight-stigma-for-disabled-school-going-children-in-musanze/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 08:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13146</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Parents in Musanze District raising children born with impairments had almost lost all hope in educating their children. Some are vulnerable and can’t afford to take their children to school. And those who can afford it are afraid to enrol their children because of one thing—stigma. The idea that their children will be bullied and victimised has forced them to keep their children away from school.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Parents in Musanze District raising children born with impairments had almost lost all hope in educating their children.<br />
Some are vulnerable and can’t afford to take their children to school. And those who can afford it are afraid to enrol their children because of one thing—stigma. The idea that their children will be bullied and victimised has forced them to keep their children away from school.<br />
Angelique Nyirahabimana is one of these parents. She lives in Muhoza Sector, Musanze District. Her four-year-old son suffers from a disability with his legs that has made it difficult for him to walk.<br />
However, he is now under the Inclusive Early Childhood Education Programme. And with gratitude, Nyirahabima says that since her son joined the programme, stigma is one less thing they have to worry about.<br />
The initiative was a result of community health workers approaching families with impaired children to train them on inclusive education and better treatment of the disabled.<br />
The development was implemented by Strive Foundation Rwanda in partnership with Chance for Childhood, both non-governmental organisations operating in the country with the purpose of helping disabled children to access early education and creating awareness on inclusive home-based programme.<br />
According to Valentine Mukanyarwaya, the coordinator of Inclusive Early Childhood Development at Strive Foundation Rwanda, community outreach programmes have been impactful and helpful to families with disabled children.<br />
Mukanyarwaya says that the community health workers sensitise the community on changing their mindset about people born with physical disabilities.<br />
“Our intention is to stop stigma and engage the community in the fight. Disabled children have rights like other children. They should all be well treated,” she says.</p>
<p>Jean Pierre Manzi, the executive secretary of Muhoza sector, has called on communities to treat disabled children in a positive way and care for them.<br />
Since 2009, Strive Foundation Rwanda has established 15 ECD centres in Musanze District to promote Early Childhood Development services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../how-community-outreach-programmes-fight-stigma-for-disabled-school-going-children-in-musanze/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>KITCHEN GARDEN STRATEGY WITHIN CHILD HEADED HOUSEHOLD IS IMPROVING HEALTH</title>
		<link>./../../../kitchen-garden-strategy-within-child-headed-household-is-improving-health/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../kitchen-garden-strategy-within-child-headed-household-is-improving-health/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 08:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13168</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[After identifying that there’s often no tradition of kitchen gardens amongst our Child Headed Household in Rusizi and Nyamasheke Districts, many people can't grow the vegetables they need for a good diet...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After identifying that there’s often no tradition of kitchen gardens amongst our Child Headed Household in Rusizi and Nyamasheke Districts, many people can&#8217;t grow the vegetables they need for a good diet. Or they spend lots of money on vegetables, or their health suffers from lack of vegetables.</p>
<p>There are several reasons why it may be difficult to make a kitchen garden, or if you have made one, it is not successful. For example: pests, diseases or livestock have destroyed the crop;<br />
• No good seed or seedlings;<br />
• Lack of space;<br />
• Lack of water;<br />
• Lack of fertility;<br />
• No spare time;<br />
• Lack of the right skill</p>
<p>Before, Strive Foundation Rwanda goes as far as constructing a kitchen garden, the above requirements are provided to the vulnerable family and after the Child Headed Household family is sensitized mentored by the assigned field Agronomist team of Strive Foundation Rwanda in-order to solve these sorts of problems, and so help the family to be able to manage and grow good produce from their kitchen gardens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../kitchen-garden-strategy-within-child-headed-household-is-improving-health/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fighting Food Insecurity and poverty</title>
		<link>./../../../fighting-food-insecurity-and-poverty/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../fighting-food-insecurity-and-poverty/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 08:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13163</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Under-nutrition in within the Child-headed Household is attributed not only to food insecurity and poverty, but also to inadequate feeding, particularly during weaning, and insufficient intake of micronutrients...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Under-nutrition in within the Child-headed Household is attributed not only to food insecurity and poverty, but also to inadequate feeding, particularly during weaning, and insufficient intake of micronutrients within these CHH that consume food rich in iron, which is critical to growth and cognitive development. Strive Foundation Rwanda, has dealt with this problem, in a way that every CHH family in Rusizi and Nyamasheke have a kitchen garden comprised of various vegetable species reach in vitamins that support body growth and development of a human being. Additionally, the cows we give to these beneficiaries have also increased milk consumption and income generation to these households.</p>
<p>The project aims at improving the protection of vulnerable CHH populations<br />
against adverse circumstances through persistent mentorship and physical support of these societies in our occupied areas of Western province of Rwanda (Rusizi and Nyamasheke District)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../fighting-food-insecurity-and-poverty/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering women for a better future</title>
		<link>./../../../empowering-women-for-a-better-future/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../empowering-women-for-a-better-future/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 08:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13158</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[“For Every country to develop, there is need for a strong woman”, because women are durable and capable of working so I want to encourage them because they are hardworking and can make it in future...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“For Every country to develop, there is need for a strong woman”, because women are durable and capable of working so I want to encourage them because they are hardworking and can make it in future, said Honorable MALU DREYER prime minister of Rhineland Palatinate during her visit at Strive Foundation Rwanda’s Huye women economic empowerment cooperative member of INGORO IHUJE ABABYEYI AND AMAHOROR COOPERATIVE in Huye District.</p>
<p>Women’s economic empowerment is a triumph of women to be capable of choosing and controlling their economic activities and incomes.</p>
<p>It is also an enhancement of women’s rights to enable them to have control over their lives and also contribute to the society at large. The main objective of women’s economic empowerment is to create just and equitable societies.</p>
<p>In a ceremony that was attended by a huge delegation from the Germany government and Embassy plus the Human Help Network President Mr. Ewald Dietrich John Baptist and his delegation visited Strive Foundation Rwanda’s economically empowered women in Huye who received them warmly at their working sites.</p>
<p>These women run different activities on a daily basis that include Brick lying and Fish farming, and these activities have highly changed these women’s lives at least to a better standard today.</p>
<p>It is in that regard that Strive Foundation Rwanda wishes to acknowledge the kindhearted partnership with the Human Help Network, Aktion tagwerk for their endurance in the journey of mentoring these women towards changing their lives and really various lives have changed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../empowering-women-for-a-better-future/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rural Empowered women</title>
		<link>./../../../rural-empowered-women/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../rural-empowered-women/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 08:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13149</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[At SFR we have observed that, very poor women need a more intensive package of services than do less poor women to break out of subsistence production and grow their businesses like fish farming, bricklaying plus some small income generating activities...]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At SFR we have observed that, very poor women need a more intensive package of services than do less poor women to break out of subsistence production and grow their businesses like fish farming, bricklaying plus some small income generating activities.</p>
<p>More to that, strive Foundation Rwanda based on experience, we have realized that what works for young women does not necessarily work for adult women. Skills training, job search assistance, internships, and wage subsidies increase the employment levels of adult women but do not raise wages. However, similar interventions increase young women’s employ ability and earnings if social restrictions are not binding. Women who run subsistence-level firms face additional social constraints when compared to similar men, thus explaining the differences in the outcomes of some loans, grants, and training interventions that favor men.</p>
<p>Social constraints may also play a role in explaining women’s outcome gains that are short-lasting or emerge with a delay. The good news is that many of the additional constraints that women face have been solved by Strive Foundation Rwanda’s Women Economic Empowerment program; these include providing capital and other support to rural women in Huye District</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../rural-empowered-women/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nutrition education in Nyamasheke and Rusizi Districts</title>
		<link>./../../../nutrition-education-in-nyamasheke-and-rusizi-districts/index.html</link>
				<comments>./../../../nutrition-education-in-nyamasheke-and-rusizi-districts/index.html#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 12:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sfr]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=13182</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Strive foundation Rwanda this year we are concentrating on Nutrition education especially Nyamasheke and Rusizi Districts where all our beneficiaries are Benefiting in this PROGRAM Thank you all our partners]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Strive foundation Rwanda this year we are concentrating on Nutrition education especially Nyamasheke and Rusizi Districts where all our beneficiaries are Benefiting in this PROGRAM Thank you all our partners</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>./../../../nutrition-education-in-nyamasheke-and-rusizi-districts/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
